Burroughs Corporation Records. ElectroData Division Records, 1952-1979. Finding Aid.
University of Minnesota Libraries
Burroughs Corporation records. ElectroData Division records
1952-1979
University of Minnesota Libraries. Charles Babbage Institute [cbi]
Burroughs Corporation
41 boxes (32.5 cubic feet)
Collection contains memos, reports, correspondence, and subject files and is arranged in series according to the origin or type of documentation.
CBI 90, Series 36
Administrative Information
Use of Materials:
Access to the collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition:
The records were given to the Charles Babbage Institute by Unisys Corporation in 1991, accession 991-35.
Arrangement of Collection
The materials in this collection are arranged into the following groups:
Medium Systems Manufacturing and Engineering Records
Laboratory Notebooks
Logic Schematics for B205 and B5000
Memory Schematics for B5000
Technical Bulletins
Engineering Laboratory Books
Engineering Test Log Books
Technical Manuals
Project and Progress Reports
Fred Kalbach Papers
Fred Kalbach and Norm Kreuder Papers
George Hare Papers
Lawrence Bewley Papers
Stromback/Merrill File
Duncan MacDonald Papers
Engineering Technical Memorandum
Engineering Technical Reports
Scrapbooks
Miscellaneous Subject Files.
Historical Note
The ElectroData Corporation was taken over by Burroughs in June of 1956. ElectroData, originally a division of the Consolidated Electrodynamics Corporation, was spun off and then went public. This acquisition gave Burroughs a good start in the computer industry as ElectroData had built the Datatron 205 and was working on the Datatron 220.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains memos, reports, correspondence, and subject files and is arranged in series according to the origin or type of documentation.
Related Material
This is one series of the Burroughs Corporation Records (CBI 90). Please see the other series finding aids for further information regarding the Burroughs Corporation.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the University of Minnesota Libraries. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Burroughs Corporation.; ElectroData (Firm); Computer industry.; Computers
Box and Folder List
- Medium Systems Manufacturing and Engineering Records
  - A4: New Products and Features Report, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B1: Type Testing, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - B2: Field Reporting and Reliability, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - B4: Type Testing, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - B5: Field Reporting and Reliability, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - B5: TADSS, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - B6: Air Force Phase II, 1996-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - B7: vs. U.S. Steel, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - B9: Test Routines, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - B10: Staff Meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - B11: Standards, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - B15: Division Budgets, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - C1: General, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - C4: Personnel, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - C5: Logic Documentation, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - C6: Consultants, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - C8: Project Cost Report, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - C9: Project Information Control, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 22-25)
  - D1: Processor, 1964-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - D2: Core Memory, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 6-9)
  - D3:Read Only Memory, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - D4: Power Supply, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - D5: Cabinetry and Console, 1964-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - D6: Magnetic Tape Controls, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - D7: Card Reader/ Punch Controls, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - D8: Printer Controls, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - D9: Disk file Controls, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 18-21)
  - D10: Circuits and Packaging, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 22-27)
  - D10: Circuits and Packaging, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - D11: Design and Automation, 1961-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3-8)
  - D12: Software, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9-12)
  - D13: Stimulation/Competiveness, 1962-1970 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - D14: Product Specifications, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - D15: Underwriters' Laboratories, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - D16: Manufacturing Cost Estimates, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 17-19)
  - D17: Developmental Cost Estimates, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - D18: Data Communication, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 22-26)
  - D18: Data Communication, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - D19: Project Review Meetings, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - D19: Cost Reduction, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - D21: Maintenance, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - D22: Program Plans, 1965, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
  - D23: Marketing Data, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
  - D24: Reproduction Units, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - D24: IC Memories, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - D25: Studies, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - D26: Paper Tape, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - D27: Translators, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - D28: FETO, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - D29: Product Manager's Office, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - D30: Disk and Magnetic Units, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - D31: Tireman Products, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - D33: PCAM II, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
  - D33: Plymouth Products, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - D34: Tireman Cards, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - D35:Emulators, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - D35: On-Line Banking, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - D36: Sorter Reader Controls, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - D37: MDTR, MTR, and MDL Cards, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - D38: Lister, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - D39: Disk Pack, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2-4)
  - D40: Tape Cassette, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - E1: B1500, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
  - F1: Varian OEM, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Advance Planning, 1961-1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Air Force Phase II, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
  - ASCII International Code, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Circuits and Packaging, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 15-17)
  - Design Automation, 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Display Units, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Foreign Plant Support, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Installation Control System, 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Memory Systems, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 22-23)
  - Product Schedules, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Standards, 1961-1969 (Box 5, Folder 25-27)
  - Standards, (B.E.M.A.), 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
  - Technical Staff, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 30-31)
  - Teletype, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Time Sharing, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Trust Bank of South Africa, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Underwriters' Laboratories, 1961-1969 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - B1000, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - B2000, 1964-1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - B2500/B3500, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - B3000, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - TC500. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Laboratory Notebooks
  - #1: Project 543, 544, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - #2: Project 1, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - #5: Project 73500 - Electronic Power Systems, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - #8: Project 543, 544, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - #9, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - #10: Project 6320, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - #12: Project - Floating Point Counter, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - #14: Project - Model 220 Central Computer, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - #16, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - #17, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - #18: Project - Dataron Computer Power Supplies, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - #19: Project - ED Control, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - #20, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - #21: Project - Standard Product Engineering, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - #23: Project 73700 (B220), 1956 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - #25: Project 73700 (B220), 1956 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - #26, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - #29, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - #32, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - #34, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - #35: Project - Standard Products, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - #36: Project - Field Engineering, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - #37, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - #38: Project 73900, 72906, 70203, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - #41, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - #42: Project 737, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - #43: Project 72807 06, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - #46: Project - Magnetic Amp Power Supply, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - #47: Project - Advanced Development L.S.D., 1957 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - #48: Project - Field Product Engineering, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - #49: Project - Field Product Engineering, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - #51: Project - Magnetic Tape, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - #54: Project - Product Engineering, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - #56, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - #57: Project - Developmental Engineering, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - #58: Project - Standard Product Engineering, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - #59: Project - Standard Product Engineering, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - #62: Project - Standard Product Engineering, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - #63: Project 6430, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - #64, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - #66, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - #67, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - #68: Project 6430, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - #69, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - #72: 753 Computer, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - #73: Project 753, 751, 759, 729, 743, 760, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - #74: Project 728, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - #75: 753 Computer, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - #129: Project 6140 - Component Engineering Evaluation, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - #151: Project 6110 - Component Engineering, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - #184, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Logic Schematics for B205 and B5000
  - B5000 Specifications, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Logic Schematics, 10.00.03.0 to 10.00.31.0. (Box 9, Folder 8-34)
  - Logic Schematics, 15.00.01.0 to 15.00.20.0. (Box 9, Folder 35-55)
  - Logic Schematics, 15.00.21.0 to 15.00.43.0. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Logic Schematics, 50.00.01.0 to 50.00.46.0. (Box 10, Folder 18-65)
  - Schematics for B205 (Box 10, Folder 66-68)
- Memory Schematics for B5000
  - B5000 Core Memory and Drum Memory Schematics, 1962-1963 (Box 11-14)
- Technical Bulletins
  - #1-16, 1957-1959 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - #17-24, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - #25-33, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - #38-40, 1959-1962 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - #41-43, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - #44-47, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - #48-54, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - #55-58/A, 1959-1960 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - #58/B-60, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - #61-71, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - #72-78, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - #79-86, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - #87-95R, 1959-1960 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - #96-101, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - #102-108, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - #109A-116A, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - #116B-118B, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - #119A-122, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - #123-126, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - #127-130, 1960-1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - #131-33, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - #134-136, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - #137-141, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - #142-147, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - #148-154, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - #155-156, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - #157-159, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - #160-167, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - #179-186, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - #187-199, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - #200, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1964 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Engineering Laboratory Books
  - 30-201: X248, X249, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 745: Log Analex Printer, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Analex Acceptance Test, 1958-1959 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 774-02: Paper Drive Test, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Character Recognition Experiments, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 790-00: Hammer Energy Test #1, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 790-00: Hammer Energy Test #2, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - 790-01: Drum Lister, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Engineering Test Log Books
  - #12, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - #19: Tape Control Unit, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - #28: 220 Data Processor Power Supply, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - #35, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - #40: 220 Memory Card Control and Storage, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - #44: Tape Control, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - #48: Cardatron, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - #51: 759 Tape Fed Printer, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - #58: 220 Memory Control and Core Storage, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - #63: 220 Core Storage, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - #67: 220, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - #72: 220 Cardatron, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - #78: 759 Tape Fed Printer, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - #80: 759 Tape Fed Printer, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - #81: 759 Tape Fed Printer, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - #82: 759 Tape Fed Printer, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - #90: 759 Tape Fed Printer, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 25)
- Technical Manuals (TM's)
  - TM 4001: Datatron 205 Computer (Field Engineering Training), 1957 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - TM 4003: Datatron Computer System Schematics, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - TM 4005: Cardatron System, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - TM 4006: Cardatron System, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - TM 4007: Cardatron Schematics, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - TM 4009: Magnetic Tape System, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - TM 4009-1: Burroughs 205 Magnetic Tape Control Unit, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - TM 4010-1: Burroughs 205 Magnetic Tape Maintenance, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - TM 4012: Burroughs 205 Magnetic Tape System Theory, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
  - TM 4017: Model 360 Numeric Code Converter, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - TM 4021: Datatron Computer Course, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - TM 4023: Floating Point Control Unit, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Tm 4024: Tape Preparation and Verification System, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - TM 4027: Magnetic Electronic Power Supply and Control Unit, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - TM 4029-1: Datafile Model 560, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - TM 4030: Model 546 Tape Transport, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - TM 4031: Model 546 Tape Transport - Type 53005, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - TM 4032: Tape Transport - Type 52164, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - TM 4033: Tape Transport - Type 53368, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - TM 4035: Model 546 Magnetic Tape Transport, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - TM 4113: Floating Point Test Routine Manual, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - TM 4115: Scanner Test Routine, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 24-25)
  - TM 4118: Paper Tape Input-Output Test Routine, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 26)
- Project and Progress Reports
  - Engineering Progress Report Narratives, January 1962 - June 1965 (Box 19, Folder 1-5)
  - Engineering Project Report, March 1960 - September 1963 (Box 19, Folder 6-33)
  - Project Activities Reports, 1957-1965 (Box 19, Folder 34-80)
  - Quarterly Progress Reports, 1968-1970 (Box 20, Folder 1-4)
  - Weekly Progress Reports, 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 5-15)
- Fred Kalbach Papers
  - Chronological Files, 1956-1966 (Box 21, Folder 1-29)
  - Chronological Files, 1967-1971 (Box 22, Folder 1-21)
- Fred Kalbach and Norm Kreuder Papers
  - Adding Machine Design Study, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Associative Cell Memory, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - B500 Product Proposal, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - B1000. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - B1500 Product Proposal, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
  - B3000. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - B5500 (Multicore Memory Technical Proposal). (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - B6700 vs B4700. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Burroughs 220 (B220 or Datatron), 1956 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Burroughs 220 (B220 or Datatron) Product Specifications, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Comparison of Fail-Soft Features of B6500 and IBM Equipment, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Design Automation, 1959-1961 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Disk Storage Oriented Multiprocessor, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Electrographic Printer (Whippet), 1958-1960 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Electrostatic Printer, 1969-1971 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Magnetic Head (Dual Gap), 1958-1961 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Magnetic Tape, 1958-1966 (Box 23, Folder 18-19)
  - Memories (Cores and Films), 1956-1972 (Box 23, Folder 20-24)
  - Memories (SAM), 1968 (Box 23, Folder 25-26)
  - Modular C Processor, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Optical Character Recognition (OCR), 1957-1960 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Processes, 1962-1964 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Product Specifications Report 75300-3, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Punched Cards and Equipment, 1957-1959 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Serial File Processor, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Small Systems, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 33-34)
  - Sorters, 1958-1961 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Sorter-Converters, 1957-1960 (Box 23, Folder 36-37)
  - Visible Record Computer (B251), 1959 (Box 23, Folder 38)
- George Hare Papers
  - 3500 Coordination Meeting Minutes, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Consolidated Engineering Corporation (CEC) Meeting Minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - ElectroData Corporation Staff Minutes, 1954-1963 (Box 24, Folder 3-8)
  - Engineering Programs, 1961-1965 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Evaluation Survey: Industrial Data Processing, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Functional Specifications: B3500, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Group III Engineering Program, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
  - Inquiry Systems (B3500 and B5000), 1961 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Product Planning: Industry Analysis, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 15-17)
  - Product Specifications: Document Sorter, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Product Specifications: Visible Record Computer, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Research Institute, 1952-1961 (Box 24, Folder 20-21)
  - Trip Reports, 1959-1966 (Box 24, Folder 22-29)
- Lawrence Bewley Papers
  - B220 Project File, 1958-1962 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - CER's, 1959-1961 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Chronological File, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
  - Computer Technique, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Electrostatic Printer, 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Engineering Change Request Information, 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Marketing Division, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - MS Systems, 1972-1975 (Box 25, Folder 9-14)
  - MS-2 and MS-3 Proposals, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 15-17)
  - New Product Proposals, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Patent Information, 1954-1966 (Box 25, Folder 19-20)
  - Project 737 File, 1957-1958 (Box 25, Folder 21-23)
  - Quality Assurance Department Status Summaries, 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 24-25)
  - Report Lists, 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Summary of Operations, 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 27-28)
- Stromback/Merrill File
  - B2800 - II Presentation, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Engineering Review, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 2-5)
  - Five Year Forecast, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Merrell Presentation, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Merrell/Stromback Meeting, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 8-9)
  - Product Management Review, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 10-12)
  - Quarterly Review, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 13-16)
  - Shared Systems, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - UI/O Meeting, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 18-24)
- Engineering Technical Memorandum (ETMs)
  - ETM 1: Magnetic Flux Addition (Robert C. Minnick), 1957 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - ETM 2: Analog Numerical Integrator (John A. Karsten), 1957 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - ETM 3: Practical Numerical Reliability (D. N. MacDonald), 1957 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - ETM 4: The Sylvania 6910 "Dekatron" Tube (Victor Walker and John H. Lane), 1957 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - ETM 5: 753 Fist Status Report (P. L. Lindley), 1957 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - ETM 6: Reliability of Competitive Computers (D. N. MacDonald), 1957 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - ETM 7: Familiarization with, and Operation of the 220 Photoreader (Robert G. Parks), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - ETM 8: Proposal for an Intermediate Transistorized General-Purpose Computer (E. L. Glaser), undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - ETM 9: Design Considerations for a Two-Diode Magnetic Shift Register (Robert C. Minnick), 1, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - ETM 10: Datafile System Reliability vs Datafile Reliability (George Hare), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - ETM 11: Evaluation of Cardatron Buffer Drum Model Mark II (R.A. Gleim), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - ETM 12: Component Failure in the Components Computer (Donald W. Pohlman), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - ETM 13: An Error-Correcting Scheme for Magnetic Tape (N. W. Bell), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - ETM 14: A Note on Transistors and Reliability (D. N. MacDonald), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - ETM 15: Design Relations in a Magnetic Drum Memory ®. S. Brown), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - ETM 16: The 220 Power Control Unit, ®. Stefansson), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - ETM 17: The "753" Computer: Logical Structure and Internal Operation (E. R. Ruterman and R. S. Sharp), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - ETM 18: Energy Requirements for Printer Mechanisms (Robert C. Armstrong), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - ETM 20: Twistors (D.C. Condon), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - ETM 21: The "753" Computer: Design and Characteristics of a Four-Transistor Flip-Flop (Jamshyd Farzan and Arnold Jorgensen), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - ETM 22: A Failure Prediction Analysis of the 220 Data Processor (R.L. Fox), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - ETM 25: The "753" Computer Keyboard and Card Input Control (A. J. Jorgensen), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - ETM 26: Motion Analysis of the Anelex High Speed Printer (G. R. Emery), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - ETM 27: Transistor and Diode Tests (J. S. Apple), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - ETM 28: Paper Motion Control on High Speed Printer (John A. Karsten), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - ETM 29: Magnetic Tape Timing System (J. R. Brown, Jr.), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - ETM 30: The 753 Computer: The Drum Memory (Robert S. Brown), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - ETM 31: The 753 Computer: The Numerical Display (Sam Harris), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - ETM 32: The 753 Computer: Card Feeding Developments (Carl Weidenhammer), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - ETM 33: Address Scattering in 220 Core Storage (G. R. Hansen), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - ETM 34: The 753 Computer: Indicators, Displays, and Operating Controls (Richard S. Sharp), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - ETM 35: 1751 Computer: Broad Description of Logical Design ®. Sharp), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - ETM 36: 220 Tape System: Operational Characteristics (David E. Hartig), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - ETM 37: Failure Rate Analysis of the 270 Printer Control (John E. Ranks), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - ETM 38: Project 743: Broad Description of Logical Design (E.L. Glaser), 1958 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - ETM 39: Linear Input Logical Circuitry (Robert C. Minnick), 1958 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - ETM 40: Sheet Metal Fabrication Processes (Lloyd C. Johnson), 1958 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - ETM 41: Corporate Costs Associated with Engineering Change Recommendations (M. M. Kaluger), 1958 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - ETM 42: The Effect of Refrigeration on the 270 Printer Control Unit (S. Goldstein), 1958 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - ETM 43: Report on Marginal Signal Detector (D. H. Hartke), 1959 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - ETM 44: Proposed Symbolic Notation for Multi-Aperture Devices (J.R. Brown, Jr.), 1959 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - ETM 45: 220 High Speed Printer System Electrical and Circuit Configuration Rules (J.R. Bennett), 1959 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - ETM 46: Some Relations Among Reliability Specifications, Electronic Design, and Manufacturing Cost (N.L. Kreuder), 1959 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - ETM 47: Dual Gap Magnetic Tape Head Status Review (J.F. Kalbach), 1959 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - ETM 49: Frequency Variations in Commercial Power Systems in the United States (George Hare), 1959 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - ETM 50: Preliminary Design of the 747 Printer Punch Control Unit (F.L. Fox, R. Sharp, R. Scruggs), 1959 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - ETM 51: Printed Circuit Board and Connector Study and Evaluation (M.M. Kaluger), 1959 (Box 28, Folder 12)